# JOSIE TA

# Graphic & Visual Designer

- Toronto, ON, Canada
- ♥ (204)-298-9528
- ♦ Josie.ta28@gmail.com
- Linkedin.com/in/josieta

## PORTFOLIO

## PROFILE

See my work at:

myjosie.ca



With **five years** of experience in the graphic design industry in Canada, I have sharpened my skills, specializing in **editorial design**, **packaging**, **brand identity**, **motion graphics**, **and web design**. Additionally, working in a design agency has honed my instincts for problem-solving, identifying client needs, and teamwork.

# WORK EXPERIENCE

#### TOM POWELL DESIGN STUDIO, WINNIPEG, MB

2021 to Present - Full-time Remote

- O Print Products Implementation: Developed and prepared print-ready files for a wide range of products, from small items like pins, buttons, flyers, and postcards to large-scale formats such as billboards, out-of-home displays, and window banners. Specialized in complex print setups, including newspapers, packaging, food truck designs, posters, brochures, and more.
- O Digital Products Preparation: Designed and finalized digital graphics for social media (Facebook, Instagram, Twitter, LinkedIn) and digital ads, ensuring brand consistency. Produced motion videos and animated banner ads using After Effects and Google Web Designer.
- Website Animation Creation: Worked with development teams to create GIFs and animations for websites using After Effects and LottieFiles.
- O Creative Creation: Collaborated with team members on branding design, developed illustrations to enhance packaging visuals, and played a key role in campaign branding projects.
- Internal & External Collaboration: Partnered with outsourced agencies and freelancers to develop animation videos, ensuring sketches and storyboards translated effectively into final animations.

#### **CREATIVE FREELANCER**

2020 to Present - Remote

- Email Marketing Assets Preparation: Designed email marketing campaigns for private schools using Finalsite,
  HubSpot, and Mailchimp.
- Presentation & Document Design: Designed visually compelling presentations for pitches and marketing materials using Google Slides, Docs, PowerPoint, and other platforms, based on client specifications.
- O UI Designing: Proficient in Figma for wireframing, prototyping, and creating responsive layouts using autolayout and component libraries to deliver high-fidelity UI designs, interactive prototypes, and design systems.

# QUALIFICATIONS

- Adobe Illustrator
- O Photoshop
- InDesign

- Figma/Adobe XD
- Framer/Webflow
- HTML/CSS

- Procreate
- After Effects
- Google Web Designer

# ACHIEVEMENTS

#### SIGNATURE AWARDS

By Advertising Association of Winnipeg

#### 2024

**Winner:** <u>Tourism Westman Park Badges</u>, and <u>Runner-Up</u>: Instacake Mother's Day Cards in the Illustration or Original Artwork (Single or Series) category.

Runner-Up: Instacake Best Friend Display in the Out-Of-Home Miscellaneous category.

### 2023

**Winner:** Instacake Alien Birthday Card, and Runner-Up: Instacake Best Friend Cake Kit in the Illustration or Original Artwork (Single or Series) category.

# EDUCATION

#### **GRAPHIC DESIGN DIPLOMA | 2018-2020**

RRC Polytech - Winnipeg, MB, Canada

- 3.6 GPA Graduation
- Courses: Digital Production, User Experience Design, Design History, Typography, Professional Communications, Digital Production, Interaction Design, HTML/CSS, Principles of Drawing, Industry Research, Design Management, Campaign, Production Techniques, Editorial Design, Illustration, Portfolio Presentation.

# CERTIFICATIONS

#### **KEYFRAME:**

- UI/UX Certificate
- Figma Apply Certificate
- Case Study: Glow Mingle

#### **CODE ACADEMY:**

- HTML Course
- CSS Course

#### **MARKET MOTIVE:**

Digital Marketing Foundation

# SOFT SKILLS

- Teamwork with & support web team.
- O Creativity to bring fresh ideas each brief.
- Highly focus on details & editorial.
- Brief analytics for sketches & storyboards.
- Collaboration with external agencies.
- O Typography, layout, composition, & color theory.
- Manage multiple & simultaneous deadlines.
- Incorporate feedback and take/give direction well.